Some icons are meant to fly.
Air is a drama, history film directed by Ben Affleck.
Discover the game-changing partnership between a then undiscovered Michael Jordan and Nike's fledgling
basketball division which revolutionized the world of sports and culture with the Air Jordan brand.
Sonny Vaccaro, played by Matt Damon.
Phil Knight, played by Ben Affleck.
Rob Strasser, played by Jason Bateman.
David Falk, played by Chris Messina.
Deloris Jordan, played by Viola Davis.
James Jordan, played by Julius Tennon.
Air is a 2023 American biographical sports comedy-drama film
directed by Ben Affleck and written by Alex Convery.
It is based on true events about the origin of Air Jordan, a basketball shoeline, of which a
Nike employee seeks to strike a business deal with rookie player Michael Jordan.
The film stars Matt Damon, Affleck, Jason Bateman, Marlon
Wayans, Chris Messina, Chris Tucker, and Viola Davis.
The project was announced in April 2022 with Affleck set to direct, as well as star and
produce alongside Damon with their newly formed production company Artists Equity.
Principal photography took place between June and July 2022 with Affleck reuniting with his
frequent collaborators cinematographer Robert Richardson and editor William Goldenberg.
While Michael Jordan was not involved with the production, he did meet with Affleck,
offering several suggestions, including the casting of Davis as his mother.
Originally set to premiere on the streaming service Amazon Prime Video, distributor Amazon Studios opted to release the film theatrically first after positive
test screenings, making it the first Amazon title since Late Night (2019) to be released in theaters without also premiering on Prime Video.
Air had its world premiere at South by Southwest on March 18, 2023, and
was released theatrically in the United States on April 5.
The film received positive reviews from critics
and grossed $90 million worldwide.
It received two nominations at the 81st Golden Globe Awards,
including Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
The film explores themes of sports, based on true story,
basketball, shoe, national basketball association (nba).
The tone is emotional.